tripcase.com 2019-05-19

# 

TripCase Privacy Statement

Effective Date: April 15, 2019                                                                          

TripCase (the “Service”) is a trip-related information and messaging service, available from Sabre GLBL Inc. (the “Company”), either online through our website at[ www.tripcase.com](http://www.tripcase.com/) or via our mobile application. TripCase provides users with the ability to integrate all of their trip-related information into one location, share information regarding their trips, and receive valuable informational updates and deals related to their trips.

Introduction

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with our privacy practices. You agree to our privacy practices as set out in this privacy statement.

This statement describes the information that the Service collects and how that information may be used by us. This statement does not apply to information we collect through any means other than the Service, actions that you may take as a user to share your information or to information collected on any other Company or third-party site that may link to or be accessible from the Service. We encourage you to learn about the privacy practices of those third parties through which you share your information or which are accessible from the Service.

Our servers and data centers for the Service are located in the U.S. We may also subcontract processing to or share your personal information with third parties located in countries other than your home country. If you are accessing the Service from outside the U.S., you agree that your personal information may be transferred to the U.S. or another country, which may have different privacy and data security protections than those of your own jurisdiction, to be processed and stored. We may transfer your data to countries or organizations that have not been found by the European Commission to provide adequate protection, including the United States. For any such transfers initiated by Company, Company takes necessary measures to ensure that your personal information is subject to the required adequate level of protection (including, for example, through use of [standard contractual clauses](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en) approved by the European Commission). You expressly consent to your personal information being used as set out in this paragraph. 

This Privacy Statement does not apply to any travel supplier, such as an airline, car rental company or hotel.  This Privacy Statement does not apply to any individual traveler’s employer or travel agency that obtains any related services from TripCase. We recommend that you review the privacy policies of your travel agency and of relevant travel suppliers.

This Privacy Statement does not apply to information which does not permit identification of an individual. You may choose not to provide certain information to us but doing so may restrict your ability to use our Services.

Collection of Personal Information

Personal information is any information used or intended to be used to identify a particular individual, which includes name, address, telephone number, email address, financial account number, and government-issued identifier. We collect several types of information from and about users of the Service, including:

  * Personal information and other information you provide to us when you register for or use the Service (including social media or interactive features of the Service), including to transact with us, or subscribe to content we offer. For example, we may collect information such as your first and last name, address (including street name and name of a city or town), email address, telephone number, and other identifiers that permit physical or online contact.
  * Automatically collected information from your devices in connection with your online activity (including, in some cases, specific location information or information that enables us to identify you across devices). 
  * Information you provide outside this application to other companies (such as a travel agency, airline or other travel provider, hotel, loyalty program, etc.) that you associate with your TripCase account, or which our clients direct we associate with your account. We may combine the information we gather, including in combination with information from third parties. For instance, when a user signs up for or in to TripCase using a login feature through another company (like Facebook or Google’s login features), we receive information like the user’s email address and name.
  * Information included in any messaging you undertake through the Service, such as sharing of trip-related information.
  * If you contact us, information you provide to us that details the nature of your question or problem, and any other information you provide.

Use of Information We Gather

We may use the information we gather to operate TripCase. For example, we use the information we gather in the following ways:

  * To provide and improve the Service and its contents for you and others;
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request or otherwise elect to receive from us or from one of our strategic partners;
  * To notify you about changes to the Service or important information regarding Company;
  * To allow you to utilize the trip integration, sharing, and messaging features of the Service, if and when you choose to do so; and
  * To provide you with e-mail or other messaging regarding additional products or services you may be interested in, either from us or from one of our strategic partners, including promotional e-mails or messages.

Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

Where permitted by you or applicable law, we may from time-to-time make certain information, including personal information, available to third parties, including strategic partners, that work with the Company such as the following:

  * Various affiliates and subsidiaries of the Company that support the Service or provide Service improvement;
  * Third party service providers supporting our business who provide services such as information processing, managing and enhancing customer data, customer service, assessing your interest in our products and services, and conducting customer research or satisfaction surveys;
  * Third party service providers we partner with to provide you offers of additional products or services based upon your trip-related information;
  * Your employer or travel agency, or others who arrange travel on your behalf, with regard to those trips or portions of trips designated as business travel by you and as such, shared with your employer or travel agency via TripCase; and

·       A successor or affiliate in the event of merger, acquisition, or any form of corporate reorganization or sale of some or all of the Company’s assets, to whom we may transfer information, including personal information.

User Sharing via TripCase

TripCase allows you, as a user, to take actions to share information regarding your trip with other TripCase users, your mobile phone contacts, or via various social networking sites (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram). The sharing process enables you to share a particular item of content, on an individual basis, to these third party services or other TripCase users by using the share functionality in the Service. Please note that sharing of such content on a third party service may be posted as activity on the Service, regardless of your account settings. To share an individual item of content to a third party service, you’ll be prompted to enter your access credentials for that third party service. TripCase may store your name, e-mail address, and an access token or similar credentials obtained from the third party service so that you are able to share particular items of content on that third party service, on an individual basis, without entering your access credentials again.

When you choose to allow others to follow your trip by allowing access to your contacts via your mobile phone, those chosen will be notified of your trip via e-mail and given the chance to set up their own TripCase account, if they do not already have one of their own. Once they have set up their account, your trip will show up in that user’s “Following” section on TripCase. Anyone who is following your trip will be able to see any changes to your itinerary (such as if your flight is delayed, etc.). If you choose to always share with another TripCase user, they will be notified of every trip and its details until you remove them from that feature.

If you connect to the Service using credentials of a third party Social Networking Site (“SNS”) such as Facebook or Twitter, you authorize us to collect your authentication information, such as your name, e-mail address, and encrypted access credentials. We may store this information so that it can be used for the purposes explained in this statement, and it may also be used to verify your credentials with the SNS. The information available to TripCase from an SNS is affected by the privacy settings you establish at the SNS. You understand and agree that an SNS’s use of information they collect from you is governed by their privacy policies, and TripCase’s use of such information is governed by this privacy statement.

If you connect to any third-party site other than an SNS using the credentials of your TripCase account for data sharing with that third party, you authorize the collection of your authentication information, such as your name, e-mail address, and encrypted access credentials, as well as any other personal information that third party site may choose to access. You do so at your own risk and understand and agree that the third party’s collection of such information is governed by their privacy policies, and TripCase’s use of such information is governed by this privacy statement.

We may also disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * To comply with law (including cooperation with regulators or officials), legal process or legal advice;
  * To enforce or apply our terms of use and any other agreements;
  * To protect the rights, property, or safety of the Company, our customers, or others. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction; or
  * If you expressly opt in to such sharing.

Location-Based Services

To provide location-based products and services to mobile application users of the Service, the Company or our partners may collect and use precise location data, such as the real-time geographic location of your device. 

TripCase also utilizes your location information in order to allow you to add information regarding your trip (e.g., a particular venue) to your TripCase itinerary for future reference by you or for viewing by those TripCase users that are following that particular trip, including your employer and travel agency should you designate your trip as business-related. 

The TripCase website, mobile application, email messages, and advertisements may use cookies and other similar technologies, such as pixel tags and web beacons. These technologies permit us and others to monitor online behavior and collect data about the viewing of that page. Other versions of these technologies may also collect information regarding your internet protocol address and type of browser, the type of operating system you are using, the domain name of your Internet service provider, the web pages you have visited, location information, and the type of mobile device and provider used to utilize the Service, as well as the advertisements and tools you may have accessed via TripCase. Access to the information available through these technologies will also be provided to our third party providers, advertisers, advertising networks and platforms, agencies and partners through these technologies. These technologies help us to improve and to deliver a better and more personalized service by enabling us to:

  * Estimate our audience size and usage patterns;
  * Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize the Service according to your individual interests;
  * Speed up your searches; and
  * Recognize you when you return to the Service’s online website.

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the appropriate settings on your browser. Check your browser help documentation to find out how to disable cookies. For further details about how we utilize cookies and how to deactivate cookies, please see our [Cookies Page](http://www.tripcase.com/cookies_policy/). Please note that certain features of the Service will not be available once cookies are disabled. We and others may collect personal information about your online activities over time and across different Web sites. We currently do not respond to “do not track” browser headers with respect to the Service.

Besides Cookies, we may use other technologies, such as web logs, scripts, or other applications that recognize your computer and gather information, such as your internet protocol address and type of browser, the type of operating system you are using, the domain name of your Internet service provider, the TripCase web pages you have visited, and the type of mobile device and provider used to utilize the Service. We may use this information to manage our websites and online services, including to provide you appropriate and better service. We and others may collect personal information about your online activities over time and across different Web sites.

Accessing Your Personal Information

You may access, correct or delete your contact information and preferences through your TripCase account. For other personal information, when TripCase is the controller of the data and receives it directly from you, rather than from your employer or another company, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access so you can request that we correct the data if it is inaccurate or delete the data if the Company is not required to retain it by law or for legitimate business purposes. If you receive TripCase services through your employer or from another company, you will need to contact the company which is the controller of your data with such a request. In such a case, TripCase would be the processor of the data on behalf of that company, who is the controller, and TripCase would follow the instructions of the controller. We may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, are impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law.

Data Security

We have implemented reasonable measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Any content, including personal information, that you contribute to be shared, published or displayed on the Service, or transmitted to other users of the Service, either via the Service or via social networking or other third party sites available through the Service, is visible to other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the Service. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of your content, including personal information, that you contribute to be shared, published or displayed on the Service, or transmitted to other users of the Service, may remain viewable in cached and archived pages, or might have been copied or stored by other users. Although we take efforts to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to the Service. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk.

Children Under the Age of 16

The Service is not intended for children under 16 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under age 16. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 16 without verification of parental consent, we will take steps to delete that personal information as soon as possible.

Changes to Our Privacy Statement

It is our policy to post any changes we make to our privacy practices on this page. The date the privacy statement was last revised is identified at the top of the privacy statement.

Contact Information

Please direct any questions or comments about this privacy statement and our privacy practices to us at:

  * _TripCasePrivacy@sabre.com_ ; or
  * Sabre GLBL Inc., 3150 Sabre Drive, Southlake, Texas 76092 Attn: Privacy Office.

Your California Privacy Rights

California law permits users of our Services that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, California residents should send an e-mail to _TripCasePrivacy@sabre.com_ or write us at: Sabre GLBL Inc., 3150 Sabre Drive, Southlake, Texas 76092 Attn: Privacy Office.

EU-Specific Notice

These terms apply to personal information collected by Company through the Services if you are an EU resident. Where Company collects information directly from you through its Services, such personal information is controlled by Sabre GLBL, Inc., which is headquartered in the United States at 3150 Sabre Drive, Southlake, Texas 76092. 

The legal basis for processing of your data includes the purposes set forth above in this Privacy Statement. In some cases, we may additionally process your information based on your consent. 

Your personal information will not be stored for longer than necessary for the purposes for which they were collected, or in accordance with applicable law. 

Subject to applicable law, you have (i) the right to access and request personal information controlled by Company, (ii) the right to request the transmission of the personal information you have provided to us to you or another company, (iii) the right to object to uses or disclosures of your personal information, (iv) the right to withdraw your consent in relation to our processing of your personal information based on your consent (however, such withdrawal of consent will not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before such withdrawal), (v) the right to request deletion of your personal information and (vi) the right to request that we restrict processing of your personal information.

You may exercise these rights free of charge unless the request is unfounded, excessive, or otherwise unreasonable, for instance, because it is repetitive. In some situations, we may refuse to act or may impose limitations on your rights, as permitted by law. Before Company is able to provide you with any information or correct any inaccuracies, we may ask you to verify your identity and/or provide other details to help us respond to your request. For the exercise of your rights, please contact Company’s Representative and/or Data Protection Officer at the location of your choice, below. 

If you are dissatisfied, we ask that you contact us first to see if we can resolve the issue.  However, if you are an individual in in Europe or certain other jurisdictions, you may have the right to lodge a complaint with an appropriate supervisory authority. The Company has identified the Information Commissioner’s Office (“ICO”) in the UK as its lead supervisory authority with respect to TripCase. The ICO may be contacted at: https://ico.org.uk/.

Company’s Data Protection Officer can be contacted at:

  * _TripCasePrivacy@sabre.com_ ; or

·       Sabre GLBL Inc., 3150 Sabre Drive, Southlake, Texas 76092 Attn: Privacy Office.

Company’s Representative under the GDPR is Sabre Global Technologies Limited, and can be contacted at:

  * _TripCasePrivacy@sabre.com_
